

CONTACT

- ***** +880 1738916935
- ☑ abdullahalfahad.bd@gmail
- Dhaka, Bangladesh

LINKS

- al-fahad.me
- github.com/im-fahad
- abdullah-al-fahad-0828b5186/
- mpmjs.com/~al_fahad
- medium.com/@al-fahad
- dev.to/imfahad

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.is
- Next.js
- Redux
- NextAuth
- Auth.js
- React Native
- Vue.js
- Nuxt.js
- Vuex
- Pinia
- Angular
- . .
- O
- Ionic
- Capacitor
- TailwindCSS
- WebRTC
- WebSocket
- Webpack
- HTML5
- CSS
- Larvel
- Djengo
- MySQL

SOFTWARF ENGINEER

ABDULLAH AL FAHAD

As an experienced frontend software engineer with over 5 years' expertise, I excel in developing innovative solutions using JavaScript, TypeScript, and various frameworks like React, React Native, Vue, and Angular for web and mobile apps.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

UMR Labs - 2023 - Present

- Leading the front-end team at Versus Projects.
- Executed several solo projects with successful outcomes.
- Deployed WebRTC for audio/video calling and online streaming.
- Implemented WebSocket for real-time live chat, enabling real-time tracking of data changes between users.
- Utilized Webpack for package bundling and build processes.
- Engaged in close collaboration with the UX/UI designer.
- Engaged in code reviews, refactoring, and implementation.
- Developed mobile apps with Ionic and React Native.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

iQuantile - 2022 - 2023

- Team Lead Developer of 'Quantibly' Web Application.
- Update existing features for v1.
- Project Planning and Execute from scratch with Vue.js (v2).
- Collaborated closely with UX/UI designer.
- Guide junior team members to enhance their skills.
- Collaborated with backend team on Django RESTful APIs.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Joules Labs - 2018 - 2022

- Lead Developer of 'Crowdfundly' Web Application.
- Project Planning and Execute from scratch with Nuxt.js.
- Collaborated closely with the WordPress Plugin team.
- Develop mobile application using Ionic and react native.
- Contributed as a collaborative team member across various projects.

TOOLS

- Git
- NPM
- Yarn
- Webpack
- Docker
- Unit Testing
- Figma Photoshop
- XD

LANGUAGES

- Bengali (R/W/S)
- English (R/W/S)
- Hindi (S)
- Urdu (S)

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

Kodeeo - 2017 - 2018

- Gained expertise in web development (Frontend/Backend).
- Collaborated with Frontend (HTML, CSS, Vue) and Backend (PHP, Laravel) team.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2022

MECHATRONICS ENGINEERING

World University of Bangladesh

PROJECTS

AI OR NOT

• TypeScript • Next.js • AWS Amplify • TailwindCSS • Node.js

SENTINEL EP

• TypeScript • Vue • Vuex • TailwindCSS • Laravel

PINTOE

- TypeScript Next.js Redux Toolkit TailwindCSS Ionic
- Capacitorjs WebRTC WebSocket Laravel

WEBACCESS

- JavaScript TypeScript Vue.js Vuex TailwindCSS Ionic
- Capacitoris WebSocket Laravel

BULLY-HUB

• JavaScript • jQuery • Bootstrap • Laravel

GUAYLLAS MAGIC CLEANING

• JavaScript • Vue.js • Vuex • TailwindCSS • Laravel

QUANTIBLY

• TypeScript • Vue.js • Vuex • TailwindCSS • WebSocket • Django

CROWDFUNDLY

- Nuxt.js Vuex TailwindCSS WebSocket Multi-Language
- Subdomain & Custom Domain Laravel Wordpress Plugin

KEENO

• JavaScript • jQuery • Bootstrap • SCSS • Laravel